I'm going to get medicine from Feng Chen.
سأذهب لأحضر الدواء من فنغ تشن.
Mother.
أمي.
Feng Chen is not a good person.
فنغ تشن ليس شخصًا جيدًا.
I know.
أعلم ذلك.
You think
هل تظن
I can't really tell you apart?
أنني حقًا لا أستطيع التمييز بينكم؟
I had hoped
كنت أفكر
to live out my life in peaceful confusion.
أن أعيش حياتي بسلام وغباء.
But now it seems
لكن يبدو الآن
heaven won't grant me that chance.
أن السماء لا تمنحني هذه الفرصة.
Mother.
أمي.
You've suffered for these ten years.
لقد عانيت من الظلم طوال هذه السنوات العشر.
I pretended to be foolish only to protect you completely.
تظاهرت بالغباء فقط لحمايتك.
The Feng household has always been a den of wolves and tigers.
قصر فنغ هو بالفعل وكر للوحوش.
And Feng Chen is no saint either.
وفنغ تشن ليس شخصًا طيبًا على الإطلاق.
I feared he might plot against you.
أخشى أن يتآمر عليك.
I also feared he might lead you astray.
كما أخشى أن يقودك إلى طريق الضلال.
Feng Chen,
فنغ تشن
now I wish I could kill him with my own hands.
الآن أتمنى أن أقتله بيدي.
The debt of enmity follows one
الظلم يلاحق الإنسان
and must eventually be repaid.
وفي النهاية لابد من تسوية الحساب.
The most important thing now is to quickly save Yun'er.
الأهم الآن هو إنقاذ يون إر بسرعة.
I'm afraid Feng Chen will find this place soon.
أخشى أن يجد فنغ تشن هذا المكان قريبًا.
I worry you can't handle him alone.
أمك قلقة من أنك لن تستطيع مواجهته بمفردك.
Mother,
أمي.
don't worry.
اطمئني.
I will protect you all completely.
سأحميكم بكل تأكيد.
It's best to be cautious in everything.
من الأفضل أن نكون حذرين في كل شيء.
Goods are hated when discarded on the ground, no need to hoard them for oneself.
البضائع تكره أن تُترك على الأرض، ولا داعي لإخفائها.
Strength is hated when not exerted from oneself, no need to use it for selfish purposes.
القوة تكره ألا تخرج من الجسد، ولا داعي لاستخدامها لنفسك.
Therefore, schemes are closed off and do not arise.
لذلك، لا تنشأ المؤامرات.
Theft and robbery do not occur.
لا يحدث السرقة والفوضى.
Thus, outer doors are not locked.
لذلك، الأبواب الخارجية لا تُغلق.
This is called the Great Unity.
هذا ما يسمى بالوئام العظيم.
Mother,
أمي.
why are these
لماذا هذه
horizontal,
الخط الأفقي
vertical,
الخط العمودي
left-falling,
الخط المائل لليسار
and right-falling strokes incomplete?
والخط المائل لليمين غير مكتملة؟
Yun'er,
يون إر.
do you remember
هل ما زلت تتذكرين
the four methods of character creation I taught you before?
الطرق الأربع لتكوين الحروف التي علمتك إياها أمك من قبل؟
I remember,
يون إر تتذكر.
pictographs, ideographs, compound ideographs, and phonetic-semantic compounds.
الرسم التصويري، والإشارة، والمعنى المركب، والصوت والشكل.
Yun'er, you're so clever.
يون إر ذكية حقًا.
But remember,
لكن عليك أن تتذكري
no matter which method is used,
بغض النظر عن الطريقة المستخدمة
each character has its own structure.
كل حرف له بنيته الخاصة.
These alone are not complete enough.
هذه وحدها ليست كافية لتكون كاملة.
Mother,
أمي.
there are so many characters.
هناك الكثير من الحروف.
These characters are so small.
هذه الحروف صغيرة جدًا.
Heaven is clear, Earth is turbid.
السماء صافية والأرض عكرة.
Heaven moves, Earth is still.
السماء تتحرك والأرض ساكنة.
Yang is clear, Yin is turbid.
اليانغ صافي واليين عكر.
Yang moves, Yin is still.
اليانغ متحرك واليين ساكن.
Observe the heart within,
تأمل قلبك من الداخل.
the heart is without a heart.
القلب بلا قلب.
Observe the form without,
انظر إلى شكله من الخارج.
the form is without a form.
الشكل بلا شكل.
Observe objects from afar,
انظر إلى الأشياء من بعيد.
objects are without objects.
الأشياء بلا أشياء.
Observing emptiness is also empty.
رؤية الفراغ هي أيضًا فراغ.
Emptiness is without emptiness.
الفراغ ليس فارغًا.
That which is empty is already non-existent.
ما هو فارغ غير موجود.
Non-existence is also non-existent.
لا شيء هو أيضًا لا شيء.
Non-existence of non-existence is also non-existent.
لا شيء هو بالفعل لا شيء.
Profound and eternally tranquil.
هادئ وساكن دائمًا.
The true constant responds to things.
الحقيقة الدائمة تستجيب للأشياء.
The true constant attains its nature.
الحقيقة الدائمة تدرك الطبيعة.
Always respond, always be still.
الهدوء الدائم والسكينة المستمرة.
Such tranquility.
هكذا يكون الصفاء والسكون.
Gradually entering the true way.
التدرج في الطريق الحقيقي.
To transform all living beings.
لتحويل جميع الكائنات.
This is called attaining the Way.
يسمى بلوغ الطريق.
Those who can comprehend it
من يستطيع إدراكه.
can transmit the sacred way.
يمكنه نقل الطريق المقدس.
Yun'er,
الأخت يون إر.
you're finally awake.
لقد استيقظت أخيرًا.
You can't push me away anymore.
لم تعد قادرة على دفعي بعيدًا.
No matter what happens from now on,
مهما حدث من الآن فصاعدًا.
I won't let you leave my side even for a moment.
لن أدعك تبتعدين عني ولو نصف خطوة.
You're hugging me too tight.
أنت تحتضنني بشدة.
I can't breathe.
لا أستطيع التنفس.
Okay,
حسنًا.
I won't push you away.
لن أدفعك بعيدًا.
Could they be deliberately fabricating lies?
هل يتعمدون اختلاق الأكاذيب؟
This paperweight, apart from its uneven bottom,
هذه الثقالة، باستثناء قاعدتها غير المستوية،
has nothing special about it.
ليس فيها ما يميزها.
Guards!
أيها الحراس!
That's wonderful.
رائع.
Mother,
أمي.
what's so wonderful?
ما الذي تقصدينه بـ'رائع'؟
Childhood sweethearts,
رفيقا طفولة،
a match made in heaven.
زوجان مثاليان.
I thought you were going to say...
ظننت أنك ستقولين...
A perfect match indeed.
زوجان متناسبان، أليس كذلك؟
Yun'er is truly as beautiful as a celestial maiden.
يون إر جميلة حقا كحورية.
As for you...
أما أنت.
Since Mother dislikes me so much,
بما أن أمي تكرهني هكذا.
I'll go wash the dishes.
سأذهب لغسل الأطباق إذن.
I won't bother Mother.
لن أزعج أمي.
Your mother was as beautiful as you when she was young.
كانت أمك جميلة مثلك عندما كانت شابة.
But what she hated most was how people
لكنها كانت تكره الناس كثيرا.
only talked about her appearance.
الذين يتحدثون فقط عن جمالها.
She despised how people
كانت تكره الناس.
could only see a woman's beauty,
الذين يرون فقط جمال المرأة.
but failed to see
ولا يرون.
a woman's intellect and abilities that are no less than a man's.
مواهب وقدرات المرأة التي لا تقل عن الرجل.
She often told me
كانت تقول لي دائما.
that women can also be concerned about the country and its people.
يمكن للمرأة أيضا أن تهتم بشؤون البلاد والشعب.
She said
قالت.
she would surely accomplish great things.
أنها ستحقق إنجازا عظيما بالتأكيد.
My mother has always been a person who never admits defeat.
كانت أمي دائما شخصا لا يستسلم أبدا.
When she first taught me,
عندما بدأت تعليمي.
she told me about
قالت لي.
a world of great harmony,
العالم في وئام.
where people live in peace,
الناس يعيشون في سلام.
and the court is just and clear.
الحكومة نزيهة.
Hmm.
حسنا.
It's a pity
للأسف.
that people only remember her
الناس يتذكرون فقط.
as the most beautiful woman in the capital,
أنها أجمل امرأة في العاصمة.
but they don't know
لكنهم لا يعرفون.
she was also a hero with grand ambitions.
أنها أيضا بطلة ذات طموحات عظيمة.
What about you?
وماذا عنك؟
Me?
أنا.
Well...
حسنا.
My story is worth telling too.
قصتي تستحق أن تروى أيضا.
However,
ولكن.
we'll have plenty of opportunities in the future.
سيكون لدينا الكثير من الفرص في المستقبل.
For now,
الآن.
I'm going to make you a bowl of chicken soup.
سأذهب لأعد لك حساء الدجاج.
Once you've fully recovered,
عندما تتعافى.
you'll have the strength to defeat Feng Chen.
ستكون لديك القوة لهزيمة فنغ تشن.
Sanxiang Teahouse.
مقهى سان شيانغ.
Exchange the bronze paperweight for Hong Guo.
استبدال هونغ قوه بثقالة الورق البرونزية.
I guess your sister Yun'er
أظن أن أختك يون إر
will come to rescue you with the bronze paperweight.
ستأتي لإنقاذك بثقالة الورق البرونزية.
Bah!
تفو!
I know
أعرف
you want to kill me
أنك تريد قتلي.
because I killed your lover.
لأنني قتلت حبيبك.
Benefactor,
المحسن.
sentimental people
الأشخاص العاطفيون
all have weaknesses.
لديهم جميعًا نقاط ضعف.
Xiao Wei's weakness is you.
نقطة ضعف شياو وي هي أنت.
He Xiao's weakness is Si Tu Wan Nan.
نقطة ضعف هي شياو هي سي تو وان نان.
Mo Ze's weakness is actually Yun'er.
نقطة ضعف مو زي هي يون إر.
Only beasts like you don't have any.
فقط الوحوش مثلك ليس لديها.
We do have weaknesses,
نحن لدينا نقاط ضعف،
but our bones are strong.
لكن عظامنا صلبة.
Success is built on the bones of many.
النصر يأتي على حساب الكثير من الأرواح.
No matter how tough you are,
مهما كانت عظامكم قوية،
you're no match for the blades of my Imperial Guard,
فلن تكون أقوى من سيوف حرسي الملكي
or the firearms of the Artillery Camp.
أو بنادق فرقة الأسلحة النارية.
I've already sent someone to deliver the message.
لقد أرسلت شخصًا بالفعل لتوصيل الرسالة.
Once I get the other paperweight,
عندما أحصل على ثقل الورق الآخر،
you can prepare to die
يمكنكم حينها أن تضحوا بأنفسكم
for your weakness.
من أجل نقاط ضعفكم.
Presented by
إنتاج
Beijing National Fashion Culture Communication Co., Ltd.
شركة بكين الوطنية للثقافة والإعلام المحدودة
Horgos Daobo Spring Film and Television Culture Media Co., Ltd.
شركة هورغوس داوبو تشونتيان للثقافة والإعلام المرئي والمسموع المحدودة
Produced by
إنتاج
Art Director
الإشراف الفني
You Jianming
يو جيان مينغ
Cast
قائمة الممثلين
Crew
طاقم التصوير
White Dot Pictures
بايديان للأفلام
Visual Effects
المؤثرات البصرية
Music Production
إنتاج الموسيقى
Beijing Landuo Music
موسيقى لاندو بكين
Chizhou Haochen Culture Media Co., Ltd.
شركة تشيتشو هاوتشن للثقافة والإعلام المحدودة